<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>School-projects on My Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in School-projects on My Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 20:39:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sr. Design Project Details</title>
      <link>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/details/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 20:39:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Senior Design is a year long course that all software, computer, and electrical engineers must take. My team consists of 6 software engineers. We have a project advisor who is a professor at Iowa State studying the therapeutic benefits that gardening can have on female inmates across Iowa. Her and her team have developed training materials and guides for the inmates so they can learn about all aspects of the garden lifecycle (planting, nurturing, harvest, post-harvest, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team is tasked with developing an Android application so inmates can take the learning materials into the garden with them, and have instant access to the information they need. Additionally, it will provide them with ways to analyze their progress. Ideally they could take pictures of plants that aren&amp;rsquo;t looking healthy, and they will be sent to our advisor so she can help identify problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big aspect of this project is the security. Iowa has some progressive prison systems that are willing to allow inmates access to tablets, but their usage must be very restrictive. For this reason, we will most likely modify the Android operating system to restrict a lot of functionality. This presents our team with an interesting challenge, as we must restrict Wifi access, but still allow data to be sent back to our advisor when the tablets are docked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page will be updated as the project progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wumpus World</title>
      <link>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/WumpusWorld/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 19:19:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/WumpusWorld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A SE 329 group project. A graphics-based game developed using Java/OpenGL to demonstrate the Wumpus World game, a popular game to study in AI courses. A description of the game can be found &lt;a href=&#39;http://cis-linux1.temple.edu/~giorgio/cis587/readings/wumpus.shtml&#39;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/ObiJuanKenobi/WumpusWorld&#39;&gt;View source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first phase of the project consisted of developing the graphical interface and connecting it with the game logic so a user could play a single round of the Wumpus game. I worked on implementing the OpenGL graphics code and connecting the user&amp;rsquo;s interactions with the game logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second phase of the project consisted of a networking component to play against friends, as well as AI components so users could challenge an AI player. When playing the game over a network, users could challenge friends to see who could complete the game with the fewest number of moves (or complete it at all). The AI modes allowed users to challenge an AI oppenent in 3 different difficuly levels. I personally worked on the AI component for this phase. The easy difficulty AI essentially moved in breadth-first manner, ignoring the statistical dangers of various squares. The medium difficulty always chose the safest path, but backtracked so it would take more moves. The hard difficulty additionaly chose the safest path, but moved in a depth-first manner so there was little backtracking and it could reach the gold quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WikiClicki</title>
      <link>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/WikiClicki/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 19:19:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/WikiClicki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A SE329 (project management) group project in which we developed a web-based game made in JavaScript and HTML, utilizing D3 graphing utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wiki-game is where a person starts at a random page on Wikipedia, and tries to get to another game in a certain amount of clicks. My team developed a web application to play this game in a more streamlined fashion. Users could choose a destination page or have one chosen at random. After clicking start, the app chose a random page for them to start on. Using D3, we showed their current page as a center node, with links to outer nodes for all links on the wikipedia page. In the sidebar, information on the page is shown so users can learn as they explore the depths of wikipedia. Upon clicking an outer node, the center node would be replaced, the current page information would be replaced, and the links on the new page were shown graphically as outer nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaceMapper</title>
      <link>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/FaceMapper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 19:18:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/FaceMapper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SE 329 (project management) group project (~3 weeks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal was to develop an application to automate attendance taking in classrooms. After being fed training images for the faces of students in a class, it attempts to identify those individuals in class photos and take attendance accordingly.
&lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/jstimes/FaceMapper&#39;&gt;View Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project used Java Swing for the user interface, and python and OpenCV for the facial recognition. Additionally, it used a very simple JSON schema for storing attendance data. I personally worked on the python training and recognition, as well as the database for saving images and information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program had decent success. It detects faces well, but can&amp;rsquo;t always match the face to a name. We believe that this was due to a lack of sufficient training data for each face. As with most machine learning algorithms, the more training data supplied, the more accurate the results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pencil Motion</title>
      <link>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/PencilMotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 19:19:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/PencilMotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A C++/OpenGL graphical application that calculates and renders the motion of a pencil tumbling through the air, and bouncing off a surface. This project was for Com S 477 &amp;ndash; Applied Problem Solving Techniques for Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class project was just to determine the position and velocity of a pencil tumbling through the air given the pre and post impact velocities and orientations when it hits a surface, with an emphasis on using quaternions to model its rotation. I used OpenGL to render its motion as it tumbles through the air and hits the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is again a class-wide project, so I can not host the code on my github.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oranges To Oranges</title>
      <link>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/OrangesToOranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 19:18:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/OrangesToOranges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A semester long group project, in which we developed an Android game based off of the popular card game Apples-to-Apples. Users could start games to play with other friends who also had the app, and create/use custom made cards and decks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our project consisted of an Android application and an Apache server running PHP. Users could sign into the app and look at games they were currently playing with other friends as well as look at previous games. We had matchmaking such that players could invite their friends (using Facebook API integration) or join a game with random players. The in-game experience was intuitive in that users could look through the cards in their hand, and drag one out to the center to play a card. Additionally, an interesting feature of the app was the ability for users to create their own cards and build custom decks that could be shared with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My role on the project was Team Lead. I was responsible for organizing and running our meetings, and keeping track of what things we still had to complete and how to prioritize them. I worked on the client app as well as the server code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for this project was originally hosted on a school-provided repository server. If there is interest, I can provide the code upon request.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dna Sequence Alignment</title>
      <link>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/DnaSequenceAlignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 19:20:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jstimes.github.io/school-projects/DnaSequenceAlignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A C++ program developed in Com S 229 (advanced programming techniques) for determing the optimal alignment for various DNA sequences by utilizing dynamic programming. Some of the main aspects of the project were:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading in significantly large amounts of data from files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using dynamic memory allocation and management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking advantage of efficient dynamic programming solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;m unable to host this code on my github as every student in the class worked on this project and it would be possible for future students to find my solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>