<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflections on My Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://jstimes.github.io/reflections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflections on My Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:39:58 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jstimes.github.io/reflections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cumulative Reflections</title>
      <link>https://jstimes.github.io/reflections/cumulativereflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:39:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jstimes.github.io/reflections/cumulativereflections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My cumulative experience at Iowa State University has strongly prepared me for a career in software engineering. My class experience has provided me with the problem solving skills to impact engineering solutions. Classes such as Project Management and Software Architecture have shaped my abilities to design systems and develop them efficiently. While working on team projects I have utilized technical communication skills. Side projects as well as the freedom of project choice in several classes have allowed me to pursue the learning of new technologies. Through those, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to apply my knowledge learned in class while also broadening my software development skills. This has developed my confidence in experimenting with new technologies in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My time at Iowa State has prepared me for the professional engineering community. I have been introduced to contemporary issues through guest lecturers and elective courses. In my project management class, we had a guest from the Department of Defense speak to us about modern software security concerns. In my History and Religions classes we learned about other less technical issues around the world. In my Senior Design course, we have spent time discussing professional and ethical responsibilities, and discussed some modern examples, such as a Ford car recall and how the engineers handled it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My software engineering education has provided me with the skills to go beyond what was learned in the classroom to learn more concepts independently. In my Software Testing class, as well as my Computer Graphics course, we were required to independently study and report on an advanced topic in the field. For each course, I analyzed profoessional journal papers written by experts in the field to acquire more understanding on my topic. I have also had to read papers and discuss with experts as a part of my Undergraduate Research Experience. My collaboration with other students in my research work has proven critical to my success. Journal papers contain technical information that has helped me understand advanced concepts. My discussions with other students have helped me to think of better ways of implementing solutions. These experiences have shown me that lifelong learning is key to a successful career in software engineering, as there are always new problems arising.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My General Education Reflections</title>
      <link>https://jstimes.github.io/reflections/gened/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 19:50:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jstimes.github.io/reflections/gened/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My General Education electives have played a role in shaping my professional engineering skills. Some elective course I&amp;rsquo;ve taken:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;World Religions&lt;br&gt;
US History&lt;br&gt;
Microeconomics&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My short term future goal is to obtain a software development role at a technology company. My long term goal is to manage a team of developers at a top technology company. I believe that my elective courses have given me the skills necessary to lead and interact with a development team. They have influenced my communication and analytical skills, and have already helped me out in classes, particularly project management. In that class, we were required to write project proposals containing details on the project&amp;rsquo;s significance and social impact, as well as economic details regarding the budget and other constraints. Lessons learned regarding supply and demand in elective courses assisted in my analysis of a project&amp;rsquo;s economic and social impacts, as well as in the consideration of ethical concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also used knowledge from my general elective courses in my senior design course. For this class, my team has been required to discuss the benefits, risks, and other information regarding our project. History and World Religions improved my ability to assess risks of projects and think about potential impacts to both users and non-users of a product, due to my understanding and study of similar situations in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My elective courses have provided me with a significant amount of insight into past events, issues, and solutions from a global context. I believe that studying history&amp;rsquo;s problems and solutions, both societal and technological, can provide someone with the ability to produce innovative solutions to a variety of problems. Meshing technical engineering skills and general electives-based innovation gives today&amp;rsquo;s engineers the ability to create both intelligent and ethical solutions to the world&amp;rsquo;s problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>